hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jared
michaelkowski and in this podcast we
give coaches trainers and mentors and
speakers a process that they can use to
scale their businesses to make six and
seven figures and what I want to help
you with today is all about your
follow-up sequences for your
autoresponders for your email list and
what do you actually send out to your
email list to follow up with people what
are some great ideas for this now I've
had this question asked a lot by people
and we have a number of different
trainings in our coaching program the
client growth accelerator that go over
this for you and how to do this here's
my best piece of advice is this a one
don't be afraid to email your list to
often people seem afraid they won't they
don't want to send the wrong type of
emails they don't want to offend their
list and they they sort of are too
Fragile with sending out emails because
they're afraid of pissing people off
they're afraid of people not liking them
they're afraid of the response not going
the way they want and ultimately it
boils down to this need for control that
people have to quote unquote do things
the right way and that need right there
is actually what prevents coaches
trainers and mentors from succeeding
okay so I just want to encourage you of
that is that a realize that you really
can't mess up with your email list and
also the people that really want to
engage with you they're gonna stay on
your list and so stop taking it so
stinking seriously that you have to have
everything be perfect on your list
before you're sending it out to people
okay now the next thing is is this is
that there's a couple couple of ways to
think about your email list first off
when you have people register for some
kind of a virtual event you want some
kind of a reminder sequence to go to
them what's my favorite reminder
sequence well here's what I would
recommend is that if you if you join any
of our virtual events you can actually
take those emails copy them and use them
to your advantage and then change the
date and text in them the the stuff in
emails that you receive in your inbox
from other people you can change tweak
and adjust and with chat GPT you're able
to use it to be able to actually take
somebody else's email that they wrote
and have chat jbt rewrite it for you and
I'm going to demonstrate how you do that
on the video version of this episode
here in just a little bit but I wanted
to talk a little bit about the
psychology of sending emails out to
people the way that we've used email
that works the best that has worked the
best for our businesses for our clients
for the coaching businesses that we've
built over the years is that when we get
people in for a specific event or
purpose and they're registered for that
event we have a series of emails that a
remind people to consume the content so
that's one thing that you want to do is
you want to remind people
if they actually registered for
something to consume the content keep
these very simple keep them the way that
you would send it to anybody else that
you know in your life whether they be a
client a a friend or something like that
like there's no way of getting this
wrong let me just explain that to you
okay you like you can't get these wrong
you're going to include a date uh a time
uh when to show up where to show up a
link that they can use any sort of
recommendations like think of it as well
when you're sending an email out you're
sending an email to a real person
to to somebody that you're trying to
connect with okay
and and so
maybe you've done this in other areas in
your personal life and now you're you
you're you're you're way overthinking it
when it comes to your business keep it
simple so reminder emails there's no
special science to reminder emails you
want to keep them just to the details
that are relevant to people because
otherwise they can actually get
confusing if there's too much
information you're not going to have a
lot of like almost any sales language
and a reminder email unless you have an
upsell of some kind you can put that at
the bottom of it but you want to send
these reminder emails out consistently
and so what we'll do is we will actually
send them out four times to people when
they register for something with us as
we will send an email out immediately
after they respond
and then we send the exact same email
out I'm going to say that again because
you probably didn't hear what I said
we send the exact same email out
four more times
all we change is the subject line
so we write one email
for our for our event to remind people
and then we send the exact same email we
don't edit any of this
in the reminder email
we don't edit any of this and we send it
four times
one day after another to remind people
what they register for and all we change
is the subject line that's in the email
so that's really simple okay
next once you actually give your call to
action in your event you want to at
least deliver a series of some
consumption emails and sales emails so
let's say that you did a virtual event
you want to send what I like to do is
sort of a one-two punch where you send
one email that reminds people to watch
the replay and then another one that
reminds them of what you're selling and
another one that says hey there's just a
couple of days to watch the replay
here's the replay of our event and then
here's what we're selling and then as we
get down the wire of exactly what we're
selling we're gonna send two emails a
day to people and you wanna probably
close the doors to your enrollment about
four to six days after your call to
action so if you run a virtual event you
don't want to have a long period of time
for people to sit around wait think
about decide not to join or whatever you
want to have a shorter period of time
there where you actually get people to
make a decision to make a solid decision
decision to actually go forward and do
something with you okay and so you gotta
send out call to action emails and you
want to be bold in these emails you want
to include testimonies
you want to include case studies again
if you join some of our virtual events I
know a lot of you have and that's how
you're on our email list this is why I
say this you can go into your Gmail
software and type in my name and
actually look at all of the emails that
we've sent out to remind people about
the events to remind people about our
offers to remind people about what's
coming up next the VIP the upgrades the
different the different things that we
are offering people and so you can look
at these emails and use them as an
example for your own virtual events this
strategy right here is actually one of
the number one things that's going to
help you be successful is make sure to
join other people's email lists make
sure to actually get on other people's
email lists because you're and and this
does by the way you're like well there's
no other people in my industry that send
emails out
I didn't say they had to be in your
industry
see that's the thinking we got a shift
is you can actually learn and borrow
from
different niches and industries
different marketers different people
that are sending out emails consistently
and you pay attention to which of the
emails that you like
which are the ones that you resonate
with
and so go through your news feed on your
social media on your Facebook and your
Instagram
and click on some ads and sign up on
some people's email lists
and then read the emails that they
actually send out and what you can do is
you can see how other people follow up
with people okay so that's if they
actually if they're signed up for an
event with you you want to send reminder
emails that they joined and then you
want to send follow-ups with a call to
action to what your offer is that lead
up to a deadline date where the final
notice is and we'll usually send like a
three hour Final Notice email to people
at that point now from there after that
and we have a whole course on this in
our members area what we like to do in
between when we have events and and
programs and trainings as we send
content to people
so it might not be an event but it might
be a piece of content it might be a a
podcast episode it might be a Facebook
live that I'm putting on my Facebook it
might be a video that I'm posting it
might be something that I'm sharing that
I created that I'm putting out there to
share that supports what it is that I
sell
and by the way it might not have the
purpose of sales at all
I will send out emails with pieces of
content
that have nothing to do with me trying
to sell somebody something just to
continue the relationship with them
because they ask for help on this topic
and so then I provide a piece of content
that's related to what people ask for
help on and so then we just send those
to the whole list as a bucket of all the
people who have actually joined our
email list to continue that relationship
with them and this has helped us grow
our business build trust with people and
provide value to our list now the truth
is 40 of our email list unsubscribes
they unsubscribe they leave our list
they they don't do anything with us
that's a normal part of building a good
email list
and so don't be afraid of people
unsubscribing don't hold so tightly to
your email list as this powerful asset
that you have to make sure that you
coddle and take care of and and it's
that's nauseating when I see people do
this is they're living out of fear and
lack and worry that I have to make sure
to be so respectful of all these people
on my list I'm sorry but it's an asset
for you to build your business and you
gotta actually use it and you can't
email your list enough we send emails to
our list and all of our clients the ones
that are making the most amount of money
we recommend one to two times per day to
the list okay
continuously engaging with our email
list showing up with offers people
unsubscribe great that's their
prerogative to do
we're not trying to manage maintain or
control the actions of other people on
our email list and I'm going to say that
again we are not trying to manage
maintain or control the beliefs or
perceptions or actions that other people
have about us that have joined our email
list and when you can have that attitude
you'll make a lot of money in your
business the reason why most people
struggle to make money with their email
list is they are afraid of
upsetting people
they're afraid of people leaving them
they're afraid of people unsubscribing
and this inordinate
focus on
it's control trying to control other
people's decisions and choices
as to whether they unsubscribe or leave
you or ignore you
that inordinate focus on that prevents
you from actually emailing your list to
make money with your list growing your
list is important sending consistent
emails to your list comes secondary to
actually growing it and so I'm actually
thankful when people unsubscribe because
I don't need everybody to accept me I
want the few
that find what we do irresistible
to connect
and then everybody else see you later
I'm not worried about making sure that
they like us or engage or continue to do
anything
that's a lack mindset it's a poverty
mindset it's rooted in well there's
never enough and I need to make sure to
hold so tightly so that I I don't lose
anything
this thinking is a root issue in our
lives that affects how people actually
do their email list the lack of time
lack of money lack of resources
when you shift into an abundance mindset
you're not afraid to email your list too
often
in fact you know that not emailing your
list enough is one of the root causes of
losing money in your business
so don't be afraid of sending the wrong
email
start to pay attention to okay what
emails are out there from people and how
could I use these to my benefit and my
advantage now I promised you at the end
of this that's going to show you how you
can use chat CPT to actually rewrite up
emails that people send you so I'm just
going to take one of my own right here
um
let's see this is an offer email that we
sent out
reminding people let's see recording
expires tomorrow yesterday was a great
training
here we go let's just take this random
email that I sent here to my list
and we are going to have it rewrite it
rewrite this email for someone whoops
let's show the screen here so I found
this email has my name on it I copied it
and again that as I mentioned you want
to join other people's email lists you
want to make sure that you actually get
on
other people's lists
so that you have access to how do you
join other people's lists you click on
ads that you see on social media and
then you put your name and email address
into those ads itself
okay
and then that gets you on other people's
email lists so then you receive emails
from people
who send you emails and then you're able
to take any of those emails that they
have
and you can have chat gbt rewrite it for
your offer rewrite this email for
someone with a Sleep Clinic
who helps clients
sleep better get more sleep
and
take care of issues like
inflammation and
diabetes
so it's going to take my email that's
all about
marketing and coaching has nothing to do
with a Sleep Clinic and chat gbt is
going to rewrite this email
for somebody else's niche
unmissable masterclass imagine that like
you you got done with the class you
finished a master class and now you want
to send the recordings to people to
watch it
I'm so thrilled to share that yesterday
we conducted incredibly insightful and
effective training session for aspiring
okay sleep coaches and Mentor so you
could be people who want to learn how to
sleep if this is for Sleep coaches you
could do that we thoroughly discuss
tried and tested methodology to earn
this much with your own sleep coaching
practice okay this is actually
written for Sleep coaching clients so
can you rewrite this email to get
clients who need
sleep coaching to watch the recording
and adjust the email itself based on
their goals specifically
okay
so the idea is you can have chat GPT
literally
rewrite any of your emails that you do
any email that you find that comes into
your inbox to fit what your offer is
what your
um Niche is here's a great one right
here I'm excited to share with you
conduct an outstanding session designed
to help us improve their quality of
sleep we delve into an effective system
of how to sleep better sleep related
issues like insomnia tackle health
concerns like inflammation diabetes
highly recommend you take advantage of
this watch the recording here
improve your sleep improve your life
here's the VIP so the idea is
that it took my original email had
nothing to do with this niche of a Sleep
Clinic
and then chat gbt was able to actually
rewrite the email
as some kind of an email to use
that could be used this way okay so what
you want to do is
it's a very simple prompt
is you just put rewrite this email for
and then what you want it to write it
for and you could also do like a whole
segment of what your original sales
letter is and say Here's the sales
letter that we want to promote make sure
to write it for that as well okay
and so that's how it's very easy to
actually write even follow-up emails and
nurture emails and all of that by
joining some people's lists some of
their offers and then having chat GPT
rewrite some of their best emails for
your offer
and then just changing some of the words
okay it's not rocket science it's not
complicated we have to stop overthinking
the process of marketing
and just get out there get some clients
and make a ton of money
it's worth it it's worth it in the end
you won't regret it follow these prompts
follow what I just showed you
follow what I just showed you in this
training obviously this is a short
training I got a much longer we got um
probably close to five or six hours of
training in our accelerator that break
down
the nuances of follow-up emails and what
to send to people but this is just kind
of an overview of what I share with
every single client that we work with
and at the end of the day it's about you
just getting out there sending emails to
your list engaging with people building
that connection treating it like it's a
platform to connect with potential
clients and actually utilizing it as an
asset in your business and it'll help
you make so much money when you actually
start to do it that way and look at it
that way
and the results will astonish you all
right listen if this episode's helped
you share it with somebody be sure to
join one of our future virtual events
that we do and jump into our client
Earth accelerator get on the waiting
list join us in our coaching program
when the door is open again talk soon
everybody